[
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 1 GCSE Religious Studies?",
    "answer": "1 GCSE Religious Studies Judaism Practices: Workbook Name:"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Judaism?",
    "answer": "Judaism is not just a religion, it is a whole way of life."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Over many centuries of persecution,?",
    "answer": "Over many centuries of persecution, Judaism has relied on family life for its continued existence and to flourish."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Children learned through their families?",
    "answer": "Children learned through their families and the practices and traditions (minhagim) which were kept, and, at times this was the only way to follow the religion and keep it going."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Much of this unit is?",
    "answer": "Much of this unit is about how religion and family life intertwine."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The halakha?",
    "answer": "The halakha is Jewish Law."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is \u2018Halakah\u2019?",
    "answer": "\u2018Halakah\u2019 is translated as \u2018the path one walks\u2019."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In other words, halakha is?",
    "answer": "In other words, halakha is the way Jews should live their lives."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It covers every aspect of?",
    "answer": "It covers every aspect of life and is quite comprehensive in giving guidance on behaviour."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of For example, it tells Jews?",
    "answer": "For example, it tells Jews about the food they can or cannot eat, the types of materials they can wear, the jobs they can do, how to keep themselves clean, how to worship, how to bring up a family, and much more."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is possible and correct?",
    "answer": "It is possible and correct to consult the halakha about everything in daily life."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Another way to look at?",
    "answer": "Another way to look at it is to see halakha as giving a spiritual significance to everything done; everything becomes an act of worship, everything links back to faith, everything is a reminder of G-d and one\u2019s relationship with G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 2 The Tenakh The Tenakh?",
    "answer": "2 The Tenakh The Tenakh is the holy scripture of Judaism, as a whole."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of There are three parts: the?",
    "answer": "There are three parts: the Torah (Law), the Nevi\u2019im (Prophets), and the Ketuvim (Writings)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The word \u2018Tenakh\u2019 comes from?",
    "answer": "The word \u2018Tenakh\u2019 comes from the first letter in Hebrew of each of the three sections."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The most sacred part of?",
    "answer": "The most sacred part of the Tenakh is the Torah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is this which is?",
    "answer": "It is this which is written onto scrolls for use in the synagogue and is read as a whole each year there."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is This part?",
    "answer": "This part is considered to be the word of G-d, written by Moses and a crucial link between G-d and humanity."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is here we find?",
    "answer": "It is here we find the mitzvot, the rules which make up Jewish law."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Torah The contents make?",
    "answer": "The Torah The contents make up the religious law of Judaism."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is believed that this?",
    "answer": "It is believed that this was told to Moses on Mount Sinai by G-d, so it is of divine origin, hence being considered the Word of G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Some Jews believe it existed?",
    "answer": "Some Jews believe it existed before even the world existed, as part of G-d\u2019s divine law."
  },
  {
    "question": "What means \u2018torah\u2019?",
    "answer": "\u2018Torah\u2019 means guidance or instruction."
  },
  {
    "question": "What means following its rules?",
    "answer": "Following its rules means that the Jewish people stay close to G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of These rules also separate Jews?",
    "answer": "These rules also separate Jews from other people in that they follow a specific path, which is true of any religion when fully followed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is This?",
    "answer": "This is part of the 3rd covenant, which G-d made with Moses."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Torah contains two types?",
    "answer": "The Torah contains two types of law: mishpatim (judgements) \u2013 laws which are obvious to follow, such as \u2018do not kill\u2019, and chukim (statutes) \u2013 laws to be followed as a test of faith, such as the food laws."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Torah is absolute,?",
    "answer": "The Torah is absolute, eternal and relevant everywhere, forever."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of At synagogue on Monday, Thursday?",
    "answer": "At synagogue on Monday, Thursday and Saturday a prescribed portion of the Torah is read."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is divided into 54?",
    "answer": "It is divided into 54 portions, and beginning on the festival of Simchat Torah, the final portion (from"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 2 Deuteronomy) and the first?",
    "answer": "2 Deuteronomy) and the first portion (from Genesis) are read in the synagogue."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Over the year, the whole?",
    "answer": "Over the year, the whole of the Torah is read from start to finish in order."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Study of the Torah is?",
    "answer": "Study of the Torah is crucial and many (particularly Orthodox) Jews devote their lives to this study."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is In Israel, up to 60% of ultra-Orthodox Jewish men?",
    "answer": "In Israel, up to 60% of ultra-Orthodox Jewish men are in full-time, state-financed study of the Torah instead of working."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Nevi\u2019im These are the?",
    "answer": "The Nevi\u2019im These are the books of the prophets; their stories and their teachings."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Prophets are people chosen by?",
    "answer": "Prophets are people chosen by G-d to guide humanity and make pronouncements for G-d; often warnings about behaviour."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They provide a historical narrative?",
    "answer": "They provide a historical narrative of early Judaism, as well as religious interpretations of those events and revelations from G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They also try to show?",
    "answer": "They also try to show the character of G-d through these events."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Some people see the prophets?",
    "answer": "Some people see the prophets as \u2018G-d\u2019s spokesmen on Earth\u2019; a way to show that their main role was to obey G-d and deliver G-d\u2019s message."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This was not?",
    "answer": "This was not always their preference though."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They story of Jonah is?",
    "answer": "They story of Jonah is an example of that, he tried to avoid doing what G-d wanted him to, got swallowed by a whale and finally agreed to do as he was told."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Ketuvim These are a?",
    "answer": "The Ketuvim These are a range of literature, from books of poetry (e."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of g. Psalms) to books?",
    "answer": "g. Psalms) to books of historical stories (."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of e.g. Daniel), to books?",
    "answer": "e.g. Daniel), to books of philosophical debate (e."
  },
  {
    "question": "What means g. job). ketuvim?",
    "answer": "g. Job). Ketuvim means \u2018writings\u2019, and they are a collection of unconnected books."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of However, there is?",
    "answer": "However, there is an underlying theme."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Every book demonstrates a commitment?",
    "answer": "Every book demonstrates a commitment to G-d which has been forged through difficulty and hard work."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Five books from the Ketuvim?",
    "answer": "Five books from the Ketuvim are also known as Megillot, and are used in specific festivals."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of These are Song?",
    "answer": "These are Song of Songs (Pesach)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Ruth (Shavuot), Lamentations (Tishah B\u2019Av),?",
    "answer": "Ruth (Shavuot), Lamentations (Tishah B\u2019Av), Ecclesiastes (Sukkot), and Esther (Purim)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Tasks: Explain the belief that?",
    "answer": "Tasks:  Explain the belief that Judaism is a \u2018way of life\u2019."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ..  What?",
    "answer": "..  What is the Tenakh?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 2 Explain the two different?",
    "answer": "2 Explain the two different types of law in the Torah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. \u201cThe Torah is the?",
    "answer": ".. \u201cThe Torah is the only important part of the Tenakh."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u201d Do you?",
    "answer": "\u201d Do you agree with this statement?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is .. 7.  \u201cHoly books?",
    "answer": ".. 7.  \u201cHoly books are not relevant in life today."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u201d Give reasons to agree?",
    "answer": "\u201d Give reasons to agree and disagree with this statement."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Refer to the?",
    "answer": "Refer to the Tenakh in your answer."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Torah has laws for?",
    "answer": "The Torah has laws for Jews to follow, but it was quickly realised that the laws did not give everyone an obvious answer to every question, and that life being as it is, it is difficult to apply the same law to every situation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Whilst the Torah is \u2018timeless\u2019,?",
    "answer": "Whilst the Torah is \u2018timeless\u2019, it still needs to be interpreted and applied if a person is to follow it correctly."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Talmud sets?",
    "answer": "The Talmud sets out to do this."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Talmud is the entirety?",
    "answer": "The Talmud is the entirety of Jewish civil and religious law, including commentaries on the Torah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Talmud The central and?",
    "answer": "The Talmud The central and key aspects are the Mishnah, which is a study of Jewish law."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Mishnah can be seen?",
    "answer": "The Mishnah can be seen in the image in the middle, in red."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Gemara is a commentary?",
    "answer": "The Gemara is a commentary on the Mishnah, seen in yellow."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Immediately around it are the?",
    "answer": "Immediately around it are the references to the Torah and the Tenakh, so the reader can see where the origins of this Mishnah come from in their religion."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Rabbi Yehudah ha-Nasi (also known?",
    "answer": "Rabbi Yehudah ha-Nasi (also known as Rabbi Judah the Prince, who lived in the second century CE) was responsible for the most famous Mishnah, which splits the law into six categories and comment on each."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of These categories are: laws on?",
    "answer": "These categories are: laws on agriculture and benedictions, festivals, women, civil law, sacred things, cleanliness."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Gemara, meaning \u2018completion\u2019, is?",
    "answer": "The Gemara, meaning \u2018completion\u2019, is the completed discussion of the law."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is written beside the?",
    "answer": "It is written beside the part of the Mishnah it relates to, and its aim is to discuss, explain and simplify the Mishnah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Around the central text?",
    "answer": "Around the central text are two sections of commentaries."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of On its left, the Tosafot?",
    "answer": "On its left, the Tosafot are commentaries which were written in the Middle Ages, and on its right is commentary by 10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 10 Rabbi Solomon ben Isaac?",
    "answer": "10 Rabbi Solomon ben Isaac (Rashi) from the eleventh century CE."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The bottom left and bottom?",
    "answer": "The bottom left and bottom right sections are more commentaries: by medieval Rabbis (on the left) and more recent ones (on the right)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In the outside left and?",
    "answer": "In the outside left and right of the page, you can see references to Jewish law (left) and Talmud (right), so the reader is able to look up other laws which relate to the commentaries or are referenced in them."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The line of text at?",
    "answer": "The line of text at the top is like a title line, telling you the page number, what you are reading about, etc."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Why?",
    "answer": "Why is the Talmud important?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the helps of the talmud is important because it?",
    "answer": "The Talmud is important because it helps a Jew to understand G- d\u2019s law and so live a correct life."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The laws are there,?",
    "answer": "The laws are there, but not absolutely clear."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They might tell you that?",
    "answer": "They might tell you that you have to do something, but not how to do it, for example: that meat has to be from a ritually slaughtered animal, but not what constitutes as ritual slaughter."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Torah is part of?",
    "answer": "The Torah is part of the Covenant made with G-d and Moses and is how Jews can understand how to fulfil the Covenant."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Time changes how people live?",
    "answer": "Time changes how people live and what people do, and even though the Torah is timeless, it does not mention many things, for example new technology."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The commentaries apply today\u2019s?",
    "answer": "The commentaries apply today\u2019s problems to Torah law."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It has been said that?",
    "answer": "It has been said that the Talmud has moulded the Jews as a nation."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Many aspects of Jewish culture?",
    "answer": "Many aspects of Jewish culture are connected to, or are based on, or are inspired by the Talmud."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of So study brings greater understanding?",
    "answer": "So study brings greater understanding of the Torah and so helping Jews to follow G-d\u2019s commands more effectively."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Midrash The Midrash is?",
    "answer": "The Midrash The Midrash is a kind of literature written by Rabbis."
  },
  {
    "question": "What means it?",
    "answer": "It means \u2018story telling\u2019 and explores the ethics and values in texts from the Tenakh."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of There are two kinds?",
    "answer": "There are two kinds \u2013 haggadah (story) and halakha."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is used to interpret?",
    "answer": "It is used to interpret the texts or answer questions which arise from them, questions which are not clearly answered from the text itself."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u2018The Talmud is really about?",
    "answer": "\u2018The Talmud is really about the conversation, and the conversation never ends."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u2019 Rabbi Dov Linzer \u2018If?",
    "answer": "\u2019 Rabbi Dov Linzer \u2018If the Tenakh is the cornerstone of Judaism, then the Talmud is the central pillar."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u2019 Rabbi Adin?",
    "answer": "\u2019 Rabbi Adin Even Israel Steinsaltz"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is 10 Tasks:  What?",
    "answer": "10 Tasks:  What is the Talmud and why does it exist?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. What can be found?",
    "answer": "..  What can be found on the outside left and right of the page?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Explain why?",
    "answer": "..  Explain why the Talmud is important."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. \u201cJews only need the?",
    "answer": "..  \u201cJews only need the Mishnah to understand how G-d wants them to live."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Kashrut?",
    "answer": "Kashrut is the word that covers things that meet Jewish religious requirements."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is used mostly in?",
    "answer": "It is used mostly in describing the food laws and to indicate which foods are edible."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The food laws are a?",
    "answer": "The food laws are a good way to keep the Jewish people as a distinct group; G-d\u2019s way of separating them from others as the \u2018chosen people\u2019."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Where do the?",
    "answer": "Where do the rules come from?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is The key sections of the Torah are Leviticus 11 and Deuteronomy 14, which explain the animals that can be eaten (kosher) and the animals which are \u2018unclean\u2019 and cannot be eaten (treyfah)?",
    "answer": "The key sections of the Torah are Leviticus 11 and Deuteronomy 14, which explain the animals that can be eaten (kosher) and the animals which are \u2018unclean\u2019 and cannot be eaten (treyfah)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of If the \u2018kosher\u2019 animals are?",
    "answer": "If the \u2018kosher\u2019 animals are not ritually slaughtered, their meat is unclean, making it not kosher."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Also, there are parts of?",
    "answer": "Also, there are parts of kosher animals that are not to be eaten, for example, the internal fat of cattle, lamb and goat, is considered in the same way that blood is (as the \u2018seat of life\u2019), to is treyfah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This used to be burnt?",
    "answer": "This used to be burnt as sacrifice in the temple."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The meat must?",
    "answer": "The meat must be clean of blood."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The sciatic sinew (which runs?",
    "answer": "The sciatic sinew (which runs from the spine down the leg) must have been removed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: All fruit, vegetables and pulses can be eaten, and with either meat or milk because they are neutral (parev)?",
    "answer": "All fruit, vegetables and pulses can be eaten, and with either meat or milk because they are neutral (parev)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of However, they should have been?",
    "answer": "However, they should have been washed and checked for bugs and insect, which are not kosher."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Milk and milk products?",
    "answer": "Milk and milk products are fine to eat, but there are rules about combining these with meat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Deuteronomy 14 (above) states: \u201cYou?",
    "answer": "Deuteronomy 14 (above) states: \u201cYou shall not cook a kid in its mother\u2019s milk."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is \u201d Observing dietary laws?",
    "answer": "\u201d Observing dietary laws is very deep-rooted in Judaism."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Many Jews keep dietary law?",
    "answer": "Many Jews keep dietary law very carefully, others loosely, and some do not keep it at all."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of However, all are at?",
    "answer": "However, all are at least aware of it."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This, perhaps beyond all other?",
    "answer": "This, perhaps beyond all other factors, has prevented the Jews from being assimilated to other nations and, considering the Jews have usually lives in non-Jewish countries throughout their history, it is to be respected that dietary laws train people to master their appetites, which is important when you think that food is a limited resource \u2013 especially meat!"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Name four animals that?",
    "answer": "..  Name four animals that can be eaten, if they are ritually slaughtered."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Explain how the dietary?",
    "answer": "..  Explain how the dietary laws have been important in Judaism."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. \u201cIt is fine for?",
    "answer": "..  \u201cIt is fine for Jews to eat non-kosher food is there is no kosher meat available."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 12 Ritual Slaughter Any meat?",
    "answer": "12 Ritual Slaughter   Any meat that a Jews cooks and consumes must have come from an animal which:  Is allowed by scripture Has been ritually slaughtered The animal has to be slaughtered by a schochet (qualifies kosher slaughterer), through a quick, deep stroke across the neck with a perfectly sharp blade."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: This leads to rapid blood loss and death?",
    "answer": "This leads to rapid blood loss and death."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is recognised as the?",
    "answer": "It is recognised as the most humane way to kill animals."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of A schochet is not only?",
    "answer": "A schochet is not only trained to be a butcher, he should be recognised as a good man and should be well-trained in Jewish law."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Kosher butchers are regularly checked?",
    "answer": "Kosher butchers are regularly checked by the Bet Din (rabbinical court) to ensure they are observing kashrut at all times."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They receive certification so that?",
    "answer": "They receive certification so that their customers can be sure of keeping the law."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Draining of Blood The blood?",
    "answer": "Draining of Blood The blood is the life of the animal (Leviticus 17:11) and is forbidden to Jews."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of So, the schochet will have?",
    "answer": "So, the schochet will have removed most of the blood from the meat by the way they slaughtered the animal."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The remaining blood is removed?",
    "answer": "The remaining blood is removed by one of three processes:  Broiling Soaking Salting Each of these processes takes time."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This has to be done?",
    "answer": "This has to be done within 72 hours of the slaughter."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is most common to?",
    "answer": "It is most common to buy meat that has already gone through the process."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Meat and Milk The Torah?",
    "answer": "Meat and Milk The Torah commands in three places to \u201cnot boil a kid in its mother\u2019s milk,\u201d which is explained by the Talmud to mean: no eating, no cooking, no benefiting from a mixture of meat and milk."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of For Jewish people this has?",
    "answer": "For Jewish people this has meant not eating meat and milk products in the same meal, or within six hours of each other (though this is reduced to three hours for meat after milk by many Jews)."
  },
  {
    "question": "What historical information is provided about we know that?",
    "answer": "Historically, we know that the Canaanite people (enemies of the Israelites in the early period of the religion) ate meat and milk in one of their rituals, so this may be why Jews were not allowed to \u2013 it clearly distinguished the Jews from other people."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of There is also?",
    "answer": "There is also a sense of compassion."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of To have a mother seeing?",
    "answer": "To have a mother seeing her child or vice versa being killed or cooked would be cruel."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This assigns dignity and sanctity?",
    "answer": "This assigns dignity and sanctity to the lives of both."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of There are many non-milk replacement?",
    "answer": "There are many non-milk replacement products now, which makes it easy to feed a mixed group of people the same meals."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Many commercial businesses make good?",
    "answer": "Many commercial businesses make good use of these products, for example, using \u2018creamer\u2019 in coffee, not milk."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Jewish Cuisine There are?",
    "answer": "Jewish Cuisine There are lengthy traditions in Jewish cooking."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Two distinct cultures exist in?",
    "answer": "Two distinct cultures exist in the food of Ashkenazi (Orthodox, North East European), based around stews, etc; and Sephardi (Spain and the Mediterranean) with its meze culture."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is 23 Tasks:  What?",
    "answer": "23 Tasks:  What are the two requirements for kosher meat?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ..  Explain what?",
    "answer": "..  Explain what is meant by \u2018ritual slaughter\u2019."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Why must kosher?",
    "answer": "..  Why must kosher meat be drained of blood?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of ..  which three?",
    "answer": "..  Which three processes can remove blood from meat?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Explain the rules?",
    "answer": "..  Explain the rules about meat and milk."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 23 Explain the argument from?",
    "answer": "23 Explain the argument from compassion regarding meat and milk."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. \u201cIt is not difficult?",
    "answer": "..  \u201cIt is not difficult to keep a kosher diet in the UK today."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of History The Synagogue is the?",
    "answer": "History The Synagogue is the place of worship for Judaism."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is a special place?",
    "answer": "It is a special place to worship G-d, It is also a place to study the Word of G-d and law, hence it is also known as \u2018shul\u2019 or \u2018school\u2019."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The idea of having a?",
    "answer": "The idea of having a special place for worship goes back to the beginnings of Judaism."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Moses received the instructions to?",
    "answer": "Moses received the instructions to build a special sanctuary (Tabernacle) in which sacrifices were to be made, and which housed the Ark of the Covenant, with the Ten Commandments."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Until the Jewish people had?",
    "answer": "Until the Jewish people had their own homeland, this sanctuary was mobile."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In the tenth century BCE,?",
    "answer": "In the tenth century BCE, Solomon ruled a Jewish kingdom and the first major Temple was built in Jerusalem, within which was the \u2018Holy of Holies\u2019, housing the Ark."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This Ark was lost in?",
    "answer": "This Ark was lost in the sixth century BCE, when the Temple was destroyed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of A new Temple was built?",
    "answer": "A new Temple was built in the fourth /fifth century BCE, which was finally destroyed by the Romans in 70CE."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of If you go to Jerusalem?",
    "answer": "If you go to Jerusalem today, you can see the remnants of the Temple, which include the Western (or Wailing) Wall, which is an external extension of the Temple complex."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Today, there is a mosque?",
    "answer": "Today, there is a mosque where the Temple used to stand."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Throughout the time of the?",
    "answer": "Throughout the time of the Temples, animal sacrifices had been made there, with Jews being required to attend the Temple at three festivals during the year."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Once the final destruction occurred,?",
    "answer": "Once the final destruction occurred, animal sacrifice ended with the practice of having \u2018high priests\u2019."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of From this point, the rabbi?",
    "answer": "From this point, the rabbi became more important, until it was made a requirement that each synagogue should appoint such a person, as a preacher and scholar."
  },
  {
    "question": "What historical information is provided about first time synagogues?",
    "answer": "The first time synagogues are mentioned historically is in the sixth century BCE."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Jews were exiled in Babylon?",
    "answer": "Jews were exiled in Babylon (modern-day Iraq) and they could not go to the Temple."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u2018Synagogue\u2019 comes from a Greek?",
    "answer": "\u2018Synagogue\u2019 comes from a Greek word which means \u2018bringing together\u2019, showing that Jews came together."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The synagogue was a?",
    "answer": "The synagogue was a place for study and prayer."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The first archaeological evidence for?",
    "answer": "The first archaeological evidence for synagogues dates from the third century BCE, with actual synagogues still existing in Palestine from the first century CE."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Synagogue emphasises the idea?",
    "answer": "The Synagogue emphasises the idea of community as it brings together the whole congregation to worship G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Also, it gave a space?",
    "answer": "Also, it gave a space for the saying of specific prayers which require a minyan (ten men), for example, the Kaddish payer which is both a prayer that praises G-d and expresses a yearning for the establishment of G-d\u2019s kingdom on Earth."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is said?",
    "answer": "It is said at every service."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Importantly, the Synagogue is a?",
    "answer": "Importantly, the Synagogue is a house of worship \u2013 a Bet Tefilah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Many Jews use the synagogue?",
    "answer": "Many Jews use the synagogue as a place of study (of scripture and law) for long periods."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Similarly, it is a place?",
    "answer": "Similarly, it is a place of teaching, where Jewish children can learn more about their religion and history."
  },
  {
    "question": "What means its role in the community?",
    "answer": "Its role in the community means that many synagogues also provide space for meetings, event and celebrations such as weddings."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 23 Tasks: Where does the?",
    "answer": "23 Tasks:  Where does the idea of having a special place for worship come from?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. What happened to?",
    "answer": "..  What happened to the Temple in 70CE?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. How did?",
    "answer": "..  How did the \u2018rabbi\u2019 become important?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ..  Why?",
    "answer": "..  Why are synagogues important in Judaism?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the role of ..  \u201cthe most important?",
    "answer": "..  \u201cThe most important role of the synagogue is as a place of worship."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of From the outside, many?",
    "answer": "From the outside, many synagogues are quite plain."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Often, the Star of David?",
    "answer": "Often, the Star of David and/or a menorah mark it out as a synagogue."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Synagogues have many windows, often?",
    "answer": "Synagogues have many windows, often at a high level to let light in, and often with a stained glass to aid reflection and worship."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They are usually rectangular?",
    "answer": "They are usually rectangular and face towards Jerusalem."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of There are a number of?",
    "answer": "There are a number of features that make the synagogue recognisable when you step inside."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of You would expect to see?",
    "answer": "You would expect to see symbols such as the menorah, Star of David, Lions of Judah and the Ten Commandments."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Also, specific furniture, such as?",
    "answer": "Also, specific furniture, such as the pulpit for sermons in certain synagogues, the Rabbi\u2019s seat and a woman\u2019s gallery/section in Orthodox synagogues."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of There are three important elements?",
    "answer": "There are three important elements of the synagogue: Aron Hakodesh Ner Tamid Bimah   Aron Hakodesh This is also known as the Ark of the Covenant (Ark) and is found at the front-centre of a synagogue and is the most important part of the building."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It houses at least one?",
    "answer": "It houses at least one Torah scroll, which is used in services and is the most sacred object in Judaism."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In the UK, it will?",
    "answer": "In the UK, it will be in the Eastern Wall, as when praying, Jews must face Jerusalem."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It represents the Holy of?",
    "answer": "It represents the Holy of Holies, which was the most sacred part of the Temple."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is In today\u2019s synagogues, this?",
    "answer": "In today\u2019s synagogues, this is like a cupboard in the wall."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It has a curtain over?",
    "answer": "It has a curtain over it (called a parokhet) to safeguard and glorify the contents."
  },
  {
    "question": "What historical information is provided about the Lions of?",
    "answer": "Traditionally, the Lions of Judah holding the Ten Commandments are painted above the Ark."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In the Tenakh, Jews were?",
    "answer": "In the Tenakh, Jews were commanded to keep a lamp burning in the Tabernacle all the time."
  },
  {
    "question": "What means \u2018ner tamid\u2019?",
    "answer": "\u2018Ner Tamid\u2019 means \u2018perpetual lamp\u2019."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is always kept alight?",
    "answer": "It is always kept alight and represents the idea of the Torah having meaning and value always, and the merit of the Jewish faith (as if a light in the darkness of the world)."
  },
  {
    "question": "What historical information is provided about it was an?",
    "answer": "Traditionally it was an oil lamp, though in modern synagogues it is usually not (for convenience and safety), and it always hangs above the Aron Hakodesh."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Many see it as a?",
    "answer": "Many see it as a symbol of Israel; destined to be the \u2018light of nations\u2019 in Isaiah 42:6, but also the idea that Israel should always exist as a nation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Bimah The Bimah is an?",
    "answer": "Bimah The Bimah is an elevated reading platform, from which the Sefer Torah is read during services."
  },
  {
    "question": "What historical information is provided about when the Sefer?",
    "answer": "Traditionally, when the Sefer Torah was read, everyone would stand."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In modern synagogues, the bimah?",
    "answer": "In modern synagogues, the bimah is raised and represents the sanctuary in the Temple."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Once the scrolls are in?",
    "answer": "Once the scrolls are in this holy place, in some synagogues, the congregation sit down (having been standing whilst it was brought from the Ark)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of People physically look up to?",
    "answer": "People physically look up to the Torah on the bimah, emphasising its importance and sanctity."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The bimah should be in?",
    "answer": "The bimah should be in the centre of the synagogue, symbolic in a number of ways: When the Temple existed, an altar was in its centre, so too does the bimah The Torah is read from the centre to show that its teachings should go out to the \twhole world It recalls that the tabernacle \twas in the centre of the \tencampment when the \tIsraelites were living in the desert before reaching the Promised Land Practically, having the Torah in \tthe centre of the synagogue \tmeans that it is equally audible \tto everyone at the service 23"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 23 Tasks: Which features mark?",
    "answer": "23 Tasks:  Which features mark a building as a synagogue?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. \u201cThe Aron Hakodesh is?",
    "answer": "..  \u201cThe Aron Hakodesh is the most important part of the synagogue."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Apart from the physical differences?",
    "answer": "Apart from the physical differences between the synagogues from different Jewish denominations, the names used by Jews for their place of worship varies: Orthodox and Hasidic Jews \u2013 \u2018shul\u2019 or \u2018school\u2019, showing it to be an important place of study Masorti Jews \u2013 \u2018synagogue\u2019, meaning \u2018place of \tassembly\u2019 Reform Jews \u2013 \u2018temple\u2019, to reflect its role as a central place of worship These terms give us an idea of the key role seen by different groups."
  },
  {
    "question": "What comparison is being made in this statement?",
    "answer": "Key differences between Orthodox and Reform Synagogues Men and women have separate sections in an Orthodox synagogue In Reform, all face towards the Aron Hakodesh when seated, whereas in the Orthodox, they face the bimah In Orthodox, the bimah is usually central to the room; in Reform, it will be a raised platform at the front, where Aron Hakodesh is Orthodox refer to it as \u2018shul\u2019 (school); Reform refer to it as \u2018temple\u2019 If you visited twenty churches, you would see that none are exactly the same."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The same is true for?",
    "answer": "The same is true for synagogues (and other religious buildings) \u2013 they are all at least a little bit different."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Local and national culture also?",
    "answer": "Local and national culture also affect what they look like, but more importantly the strand or branch of the religion that the building belongs to has an impact on what it will look like."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u201cThe synagogue is, most?",
    "answer": "\u201cThe synagogue is, most importantly, a place of study."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Every aspect of Jewish life?",
    "answer": "Every aspect of Jewish life can be seen as an act of worship \u2013 devotion to G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Many acts of worship take?",
    "answer": "Many acts of worship take place in the synagogue, however many also take place at home."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Worship in the Synagogue Daily?",
    "answer": "Worship in the Synagogue Daily Service Festivals Israel Dependence Day Holocaust Memorial Shabbat Marriage Funeral Bar/Bat Mitzvah Yarhzeit Prayers for the Sick Study Worship in the Home 23 Circumcision Festivals Children's Prayer Shabbat Havdalah Meals (thanksgiving) Mourning Period (Shiva) Dedication of Home Anniversaries Prayers for the Sick Study"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 23 As you can see?",
    "answer": "23 As you can see from the diagrams, there are areas of overlap that reinforce the idea that the home and family are key to the Jewish faith."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It forms a part of?",
    "answer": "It forms a part of the Covenant with Abraham, so is a duty It shows devotion It is a mitzvot; a law to keep It keeps a person mindful of G-d\u2019s presence throughout the day It is an act of praise to G-d It brings a community together Jews can worship G-d at anytime and anywhere."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of A simple prayer?",
    "answer": "A simple prayer might be said."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They might take part in?",
    "answer": "They might take part in congregational worship (public) or they might devote time to religious study."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They might dedicate any actions?",
    "answer": "They might dedicate any actions to G-d as an act of worship."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Which types of worship?",
    "answer": "..  Which types of worship can be done in the synagogue that cannot be done at home?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ..  Explain why worship?",
    "answer": "..  Explain why worship is important to Jewish people."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Being dressed ready for worship?",
    "answer": "Being dressed ready for worship Jews wear a kippah, tallit and tefillin for prayer."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Most of the men in?",
    "answer": "Most of the men in an Orthodox act of worship will wear all three, though few in Reform synagogues will."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of All males will have their?",
    "answer": "All males will have their head covered, usually by a kippah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of However, it is crucial that?",
    "answer": "However, it is crucial that people attending the synagogue dress well and they do not wear scruffy clothes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They should take?",
    "answer": "They should take care of their appearance."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Key People The rabbi is?",
    "answer": "Key People The rabbi is the spiritual leader of a Jewish community."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They may lead worship, though?",
    "answer": "They may lead worship, though as it is scripted, others can also."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This person (always male in?",
    "answer": "This person (always male in Orthodox synagogues) must be of good character and will have studies Jewish law and teachings to a very high level at a yeshivah (Torah school) and then rabbinical school."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They are often aided by?",
    "answer": "They are often aided by a cantor, who sings at points throughout the service, leading the congregation through prayer, particularly at Shabbat and festival services."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of There has to be a?",
    "answer": "There has to be a group of ten adults for an act of worship to take place, this is called a minyan."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Structure of Worship Worship?",
    "answer": "The Structure of Worship Worship is built around the reciting of different prayers."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Two books?",
    "answer": "Two books are key: the siddur (or prayer book), which details the words and prayers which are said throughout a service, and the chamash, which is the Torah in printed form."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Depending on which prayer-time in?",
    "answer": "Depending on which prayer-time in the day, the prayers said will vary."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is The key prayers are the Shema, the Amidah (18 blessings), the Kaddish and the Aleinu prayers?",
    "answer": "The key prayers are the Shema, the Amidah (18 blessings), the Kaddish and the Aleinu prayers."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of On Monday and Thursday, a?",
    "answer": "On Monday and Thursday, a portion of the Torah is read, whilst on Saturday, both the Torah and the Haftorah (Prophecies) are read."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of There are differences between?",
    "answer": "There are differences between the different groups within Judaism."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of For example, the number of?",
    "answer": "For example, the number of prayers and reading, and the exact choice of them all vary."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Not every synagogue has its?",
    "answer": "Not every synagogue has its own rabbi or cantor \u2013 anyone can lead the service (as long as they are of good character and knowledgeable about faith)."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ..  Who?",
    "answer": "..  Who is the rabbi and who is the cantor?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ..  Which two books?",
    "answer": "..  Which two books are key to Jewish worship?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. \u201cJews should dress?",
    "answer": "..  \u201cJews should dress well to attend synagogue."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Hebrew word for prayer?",
    "answer": "The Hebrew word for prayer is \u2018tefillah\u2019 and comes from a word that mean to judge oneself."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This shows that, for Jews,?",
    "answer": "This shows that, for Jews, prayer should be a time for reflection and thinking about how they are doing in their relationship with G-d, and in following their duties on Earth and not about begging G-d to change things."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of There are many prayers, blessings?",
    "answer": "There are many prayers, blessings and benedictions used in Judaism."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In this guide, we will?",
    "answer": "In this guide, we will look at four \u2013 all of which are used in synagogue services."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They are all found in?",
    "answer": "They are all found in the Siddur (prayer book), so it is not necessary to know them by heart."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of However, many?",
    "answer": "However, many Jews learn them."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is not just?",
    "answer": "It is not just about the worlds, though."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Judaism has many traditions (minhagim),?",
    "answer": "Judaism has many traditions (minhagim), and these along with the teaching of rabbis, have also shaped how the prayers are said and what is done whilst saying them."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Shema This is?",
    "answer": "The Shema This is the declaration of faith."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u2018Shema\u2019 is the first word?",
    "answer": "\u2018Shema\u2019 is the first word in Hebrew of this declaration, meaning \u2018hear\u2019 or \u2018listen\u2019."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It must be recited three?",
    "answer": "It must be recited three times daily in prayer, but it is a duty to recite it generally during the day as well."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Shema is taken directly?",
    "answer": "The Shema is taken directly from three paragraphs in the Torah: two from Deuteronomy and one from Numbers."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The way the Shema is?",
    "answer": "The way the Shema is said varies: Orthodox Jews see it as study, so remain seated; Reform Jews stand during the Shema as a form of respect."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: All Jews say it aloud and clearly, because they are saying the basic beliefs of their faith?",
    "answer": "All Jews say it aloud and clearly, because they are saying the basic beliefs of their faith."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is common to see?",
    "answer": "It is common to see Jews close/cover their eyes to focus completely on the words in the first verse of the Shema, as Jewish law demands this level of concentration."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is also common to?",
    "answer": "It is also common to see those wearing tallit holding the tzitzit (fringes) in their left hand whilst reciting the Shema."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In its third paragraph, it?",
    "answer": "In its third paragraph, it mentions these three times, so it has become a custom to kiss the tzitzit as a sign of affection for the law, after the last word of the Shema has been said."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of What does?",
    "answer": "What does the Shema say?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It begins, \u2018Hear, O Israel,?",
    "answer": "It begins, \u2018Hear, O Israel, the Lord is our G-d, the Lord is One G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is \u2019 This?",
    "answer": "\u2019 This is a fundamental belief of Judaism, from which all other beliefs and the law flow."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Then there is a sentence,?",
    "answer": "Then there is a sentence, \u2018Blessed is the name of His Glorious Majesty forever and ever."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u2019 This used to be?",
    "answer": "\u2019 This used to be said by the congregation in the temple in Jerusalem after the priests had said the first sentence."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is not actually from?",
    "answer": "It is not actually from the Torah, so it is said quietly."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Then there are three?",
    "answer": "Then there are three paragraphs, all from the Torah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of These are about: G-d and?",
    "answer": "These are about: G-d and religious duties to demonstrate love to G-d; about accepting the laws and the consequences of breaking or following them; about the mitzvot to wear tzitzit, mentioning the Exodus from Egypt."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Differences in Jewish Denominations Reform?",
    "answer": "Differences in Jewish Denominations Reform Jews in the USA do not include all of the second two of these passages \u2013 they have a different idea about G-d\u2019s retribution (what G-d will do if the mitzvot are not followed), and do not accept the mitzvot to wear tzitzit, so these parts are omitted from their Siddur."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of British Reform Jews,?",
    "answer": "British Reform Jews, however, say them."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is 23 Tasks:  For Jews, what?",
    "answer": "23 Tasks:  For Jews, what is prayer a time for?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Where can?",
    "answer": "..  Where can the prayers be found?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Explain how the?",
    "answer": "..  Explain how the Shema prayer is said."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Explain what?",
    "answer": "..  Explain what the Shema prayer says."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The correct term for this?",
    "answer": "The correct term for this prayer is the Shemonah Esreh or the 18 blessings."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: It is known as the Amidah because it is said whilst standing, and \u2018Amidah\u2019 means \u2018standing\u2019?",
    "answer": "It is known as the Amidah because it is said whilst standing, and \u2018Amidah\u2019 means \u2018standing\u2019."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of There are actually 19?",
    "answer": "There are actually 19 blessing within the prayer now."
  },
  {
    "question": "What historical information is provided about a new blessing?",
    "answer": "Traditionally, a new blessing was added as significant things happened throughout history."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of By 5th Century BCE,?",
    "answer": "By 5th Century BCE, 18 blessings were in place."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The 19th was added?",
    "answer": "The 19th was added in the 1st Century CE."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The blessings take a specific?",
    "answer": "The blessings take a specific and logical order, so they start with being clear on how important G-d is, far beyond humans, moving through limitations of being human, to the request to accept prayers and the hope for peace."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They can also be split?",
    "answer": "They can also be split into three groups: three blessings of praise, then 13 of requests and, finally, three of gratitude."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Most Jews follow the views?",
    "answer": "Most Jews follow the views of Maimonides (the man responsible for the Mishneh Torah) on how they say the Amidah) always standing, always facing Jerusalem)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of I Samuel 1:13 says that?",
    "answer": "I Samuel 1:13 says that Hannah spoke to G-d merely by moving her lips \u2013 soundless \u2013 and so the Amidah is said in that way, as if the sound comes from the heart."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of During the prayer, rabbis have?",
    "answer": "During the prayer, rabbis have ruled Jews must bend their knee at the words Barukh, then bow at Attah, standing up straight at Adonai."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Amidah is very sacred,?",
    "answer": "The Amidah is very sacred, as is the person\u2019s space when saying it, so it is traditional to take three steps forward and back before beginning."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of At the end of the?",
    "answer": "At the end of the prayer, a Jew bows to the left, then to the right, and once again takes three steps backwards."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Both actions represent approaching and?",
    "answer": "Both actions represent approaching and leaving the presence of the King/Queen."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They only return to their?",
    "answer": "They only return to their original place when the cantor begins his repetition of the Amidah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of During this, the congregation will?",
    "answer": "During this, the congregation will say \u2018Amen\u2019 after each blessing."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Amidah is modified for?",
    "answer": "The Amidah is modified for special occasions, for example, on Shabbat or on a festival celebration, but will always keep the first and last three blessings the same."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is said during each?",
    "answer": "It is said during each of the three daily prayers."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Once begun, it?",
    "answer": "Once begun, it must be completed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ..  How many blessings?",
    "answer": "..  How many blessings are in the Amidah and how were they included?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the responsible of ..  who was?",
    "answer": "..  Who was responsible for the Mishneh Torah?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Why do you think?",
    "answer": ".. Why do you think the Amidah must be finished, once started?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Explain your opinion, showing an?",
    "answer": "Explain your opinion, showing an awareness of at least one other point of view."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is a hymn of?",
    "answer": "It is a hymn of praises to G-d, beginning \u2018May His great name be exalted\u2026\u2019 It can only be said if there is a minyan (ten men), as with the Amidah, so is recited at the synagogue each prayer time each day."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is?",
    "answer": "It is in the Siddur."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of There are different Kaddishes, the?",
    "answer": "There are different Kaddishes, the most commonly known being the mourner\u2019s Kaddish."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of A Midrashic text explains its?",
    "answer": "A Midrashic text explains its value to the deceased, but Jewish scholars have also shown it is of value to the living."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Essentially, the congregation are praising?",
    "answer": "Essentially, the congregation are praising G-d to remin d themselves that death and loss are part of a greater plan, so words of the Kaddish in praising G-d help mourners restore their own faith and attachment to G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Kaddish is?",
    "answer": "The Kaddish is recited aloud whilst standing."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is a call and?",
    "answer": "It is a call and response prayer, which means that one person says a phrase from the prayer and the congregation make a response."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Prayer \u2013 The Aleinu The?",
    "answer": "Prayer \u2013 The Aleinu The Aleinu is a closing prayer of a synagogue service, and actually combines two prayers."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: It is a prayer to praise G-d and restate a Jew\u2019s dedication to G-d as one of the chosen people for whom there are many difficulties because of that choosing?",
    "answer": "It is a prayer to praise G-d and restate a Jew\u2019s dedication to G-d as one of the chosen people for whom there are many difficulties because of that choosing."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It also reminds everyone that?",
    "answer": "It also reminds everyone that G-d\u2019s rule is without end \u2013 eternal."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of On ending the service, each?",
    "answer": "On ending the service, each person is reminded of G-d, His power and splendour; that all hope is in G-d and the wish to see G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They are making a commitment?",
    "answer": "They are making a commitment to G-d, dedicating themselves again to Him."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of As a mark of that?",
    "answer": "As a mark of that commitment, many Jews will bow their knee towards the Aron Hakodesh, as if they are bowing to G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 23 Tasks: What?",
    "answer": "23 Tasks:  What does \u2018Kaddish\u2019 mean?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ..  Which?",
    "answer": "..  Which is the most commonly known Kaddish?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ..  How?",
    "answer": "..  How is the Kaddish recited?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Explain the importance?",
    "answer": "..  Explain the importance of the Aleinu prayer."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Not every Jew can get?",
    "answer": "Not every Jew can get to the synagogues to pray for each of the required three prayer- times."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Also, women do not attend?",
    "answer": "Also, women do not attend synagogue except for on Shabbat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Therefore, private worship?",
    "answer": "Therefore, private worship is common in Judaism."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Since worship?",
    "answer": "Since worship is based around prayer, it is a case of saying prayers which do not require a minyan (ten men)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of These are personal prayers, which?",
    "answer": "These are personal prayers, which require a person to be suitably prepared for prayer (both mentally and in appearance)."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Kavanah?",
    "answer": "Kavanah is the mind-set for prayer."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is about having?",
    "answer": "It is about having the right intention and focus."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Just repeating the same prayers?",
    "answer": "Just repeating the same prayers daily might lead a person to repeat them mindlessly and unthinkingly, so people need to have the right mind-set."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Additionally, a person should be?",
    "answer": "Additionally, a person should be clean and tidy for their prayer as a sign of respect for G-d and for what they are about to do."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Kippah Also?",
    "answer": "Kippah Also called a Yarmulke."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Covering the head is the?",
    "answer": "Covering the head is the Jewish way of showing respect, and to pray with the head uncovered would be breaking important rules of faith."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Tallit and Tzitzit The tallit?",
    "answer": "Tallit and Tzitzit The tallit is a prayer shawl with four corners and a hole in each corner."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of However, once the tzitzit (fringes)?",
    "answer": "However, once the tzitzit (fringes) are attached, it becomes a sacred item, fit for prayer."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is common for there?",
    "answer": "It is common for there to be blue in a prayer shawl, which represents G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of However, some Jews wear an?",
    "answer": "However, some Jews wear an all-white tallit, showing atonement and forgiveness."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Jews will wear the tallit?",
    "answer": "Jews will wear the tallit across their shoulders and some over their heads when praying."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It has to cover the?",
    "answer": "It has to cover the body, hence the practice of very large shawls being used."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This represents that the person?",
    "answer": "This represents that the person wants to wrap themselves in G-d\u2019s will."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is the custom of?",
    "answer": "It is the custom of many denominations of Judaism that a man only begins to wear the tallit regularly after marriage; however, some Jews wear the tallit from their Bar Mitzvah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The tzitzit are the fringes?",
    "answer": "The tzitzit are the fringes which are affixed to each of the four corners of the tallit."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They are twisted strands, tied?",
    "answer": "They are twisted strands, tied and knotted, which hang loose."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of ~They represent the mitzvot, as?",
    "answer": "~They represent the mitzvot, as well as the four corners of the Earth; the idea is that the commandments are relevant everywhere."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Specific prayers, for example, when?",
    "answer": "Specific prayers, for example, when reciting the Keriat Shema (Shema in Hebrew), require the holding of tzitzit in the left hand opposite the heart to show love for G-d and the commandments and as a physical reminder of the commandments."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Tefillin These are two small?",
    "answer": "Tefillin These are two small boxes with straps which are worn on the forehead and arm."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Each contains parchment on which?",
    "answer": "Each contains parchment on which is written four passages from the Torah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They are on one strip?",
    "answer": "They are on one strip for the arm and individual parchments for the head."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of These items are put?",
    "answer": "These items are put on after the tallit."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of When being put on, the?",
    "answer": "When being put on, the tefillin help the wearer to focus their mind on the act of praying."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Prayers?",
    "answer": "Prayers are said at each stage as the items are put on."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The arm tefillah points to?",
    "answer": "The arm tefillah points to the body, towards the heart, as a reminder of G-d\u2019s love and of love for G-d and the commandments."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The head tefillah symbolises?",
    "answer": "The head tefillah symbolises constant awareness of G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is important for Jews?",
    "answer": "It is important for Jews to wear tefillin for prayer."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Talmud says many?",
    "answer": "The Talmud says many times that they must."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The tefillin help a Jew?",
    "answer": "The tefillin help a Jew to focus on their past history, present duties to keep the mitzvot and their future destiny."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: Having said that, Shabbat does not require the wearing of tefillin because the day already symbolises the Covenant with G-d?",
    "answer": "Having said that, Shabbat does not require the wearing of tefillin because the day already symbolises the Covenant with G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Siddur The Siddur is the?",
    "answer": "Siddur The Siddur is the prayer book with all the prayers and words to be read at any prayer time."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is the guide for?",
    "answer": "It is the guide for the period of prayer to be carried out."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. 6. \u201cIt isn\u2019t?",
    "answer": ".. 6.  \u201cIt isn\u2019t necessary to dress for prayer."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Jews pray three?",
    "answer": "Jews pray three times every day."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The first prayer is?",
    "answer": "The first prayer is shacharit, in the morning."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It recalls when sacrifices were?",
    "answer": "It recalls when sacrifices were made in the temple, and when Abraham chose to pray."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of He wanted to start his?",
    "answer": "He wanted to start his day with G-d, which then set him up to follow G-d\u2019s commands."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The afternoon prayer is minchah,?",
    "answer": "The afternoon prayer is minchah, to reflect when afternoon sacrifice took place in the temple and follows Isaac\u2019s timing for prayer."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The pray to G-d at?",
    "answer": "The pray to G-d at this time is to interrupt the day and remind oneself of G-d\u2019s supreme importance."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The evening prayer is?",
    "answer": "The evening prayer is maariv, after Jacob\u2019s practice."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of By praying in the evening,?",
    "answer": "By praying in the evening, Jews can ensure that G-d is the last thing on their minds before going to sleep."
  },
  {
    "question": "What historical information is provided about Shabbat, High Holy?",
    "answer": "On Shabbat, High Holy Days and the new Moon, as additional prayer, musaf, is added, traditionally combines with the shacharit prayer."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This parallels the extra sacrifice?",
    "answer": "This parallels the extra sacrifice that was brought in the temple."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: The importance of prayer Jews pray because: It is a mitzvot (commandment) It shows devotion to G-d and a desire to be close to G-d It allows them to do what is right It allows them to get into the right frame of mind for prayer It allows them to prepare for the day and reflect on the day It is tradition: Jews have prayed since the start of the faith and many of the prayer \tcome from historical times 23?",
    "answer": "The importance of prayer Jews pray because: It is a mitzvot (commandment) It shows devotion to G-d and a desire to be close to G-d It allows them to do what is right It allows them to get into the right frame of mind for prayer It allows them to prepare for the day and reflect on the day It is tradition: Jews have prayed since the start of the faith and many of the prayer \tcome from historical times 23"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Prayers link Jews with the?",
    "answer": "Prayers link Jews with the Jewish community \u2013 past, present \tand future Prayer is a cleansing act, giving a sense of well-being and \tpurification It is communication with G-d Prayer at home versus prayer in the synagogue In Judaism, prayer is also about communicating with G-d, but also with other Jews."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: The rabbis said that congregational prayer was more important because the most important prayers (Amidah, Kaddish, Baruch Hu) all demand a minyan (ten men) for their recitation?",
    "answer": "The rabbis said that congregational prayer was more important because the most important prayers (Amidah, Kaddish, Baruch Hu) all demand a minyan (ten men) for their recitation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Maimonides said that G-d always?",
    "answer": "Maimonides said that G-d always answers the prayers of a community."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Additionally, the language of the?",
    "answer": "Additionally, the language of the prayers is to say \u2018us\u2019 rather than \u2018I\u2019, which shows that a group should be saying the prayer, not the individual."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of However, in many traditions of?",
    "answer": "However, in many traditions of Judaism, women do not attend the synagogue other than for the Shabbat service, so they might have a much-reduced chance to pray in this way."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Some might say this?",
    "answer": "Some might say this is not fair."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Additionally, G-d sees everything and?",
    "answer": "Additionally, G-d sees everything and so it should be possible to pray anywhere at any time."
  },
  {
    "question": "What means this?",
    "answer": "This means it actually does not matter where prayers are said, or how they are said, what matters is the sincerity of them."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of G-d being everywhere is?",
    "answer": "G-d being everywhere is known as G-d\u2019s \u2018omnipresence\u2019."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: The image on the left, although comical, wouldn\u2019t be acceptable in Judaism because no images or drawings of G-d are permitted: \u201cDo not make false images?",
    "answer": "The image on the left, although comical, wouldn\u2019t be acceptable in Judaism because no images or drawings of G-d are permitted: \u201cDo not make false images."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 23 Tasks: Explain the?",
    "answer": "23 Tasks:  Explain the reason behind several daily prayers."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ..  Explain why prayer?",
    "answer": "..  Explain why prayer is important for Jews."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. \u201cAll prayer should?",
    "answer": "..  \u201cAll prayer should take place in the synagogue."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Exodus 31: 16-17 \u201cAnd the?",
    "answer": "Exodus 31: 16-17 \u201cAnd the children of Israel shall keep the Sabbath to observe the Sabbath throughout the generations, for a perpetual covenant."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is a sign between?",
    "answer": "It is a sign between Me and the Children of Israel forever, for six days the Lord made Heaven and Earth, and on the seventh say He ceased from work and rested."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u201d Deuteronomy 20:8 \u201cRemember the?",
    "answer": "\u201d Deuteronomy 20:8 \u201cRemember the Sabbath Day to keep it holy\u2026 for six days the Lord made Heaven and Earth, and rested on the seventh day."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u201d Exodus 20: 9-10 \u201cSix?",
    "answer": "\u201d Exodus 20: 9-10 \u201cSix days you shall labour and do all your work; but on the seventh day, which is a Sabbath in honour of the Lord your G-d, you shall not so any work, neither you, nor your son, nor your daughter, nor our male or female servant, nor your cattle, nor the stranger who is within your gates."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is \u201d About Shabbat Shabbat?",
    "answer": "\u201d About Shabbat Shabbat is the Jewish day of rest, beginning at sundown on Friday and ending when the starts are out on Saturday evening."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: Jews keep Shabbat because they must \u2013 it is a commandment and part of their Covenant with G-d?",
    "answer": "Jews keep Shabbat because they must \u2013 it is a commandment and part of their Covenant with G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It reminds them that G-d?",
    "answer": "It reminds them that G-d created the world and they are copying G- d\u2019s example of resting from important work."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is the only ritual?",
    "answer": "It is the only ritual mentioned in the Commandments: Remember the Sabbath day, to keep it holy."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Families have passed on the?",
    "answer": "Families have passed on the traditions and laws of Shabbat to their children."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Not working on Shabbat The?",
    "answer": "Not working on Shabbat The Talmud forbids 39 areas of work on Shabbat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Many people think that \u2018work\u2019?",
    "answer": "Many people think that \u2018work\u2019 can mean anything you do, but \u2018work\u2019 only actually covers melachah tasks (creative tasks, or ones that exercise control over a person\u2019s environment)."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is This word?",
    "answer": "This word is only used in the Torah in terms of Shabbat and building the Tabernacle, so the rabbis worked out the categories 23"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of of forbidden work from what?",
    "answer": "of forbidden work from what was needed to build the Tabernacle."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of However, the principle of pikuach?",
    "answer": "However, the principle of pikuach nefesh (to save a life) overrides Shabbat rules on work."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Getting ready for Shabbat Shabbat?",
    "answer": "Getting ready for Shabbat Shabbat is a sacred time, so a person cannot just go straight from the hassle of work into the peace of Shabbat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Most Jews shop for the?",
    "answer": "Most Jews shop for the Shabbat meals on Friday morning; meals taken on the day are light so as to make the evening meal taste even better."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Additionally, Jews have to prepare?",
    "answer": "Additionally, Jews have to prepare for Shabbat so that they avoid breaking the rules around work."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Many things have to be?",
    "answer": "Many things have to be prepared or put into place ahead of Shabbat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of For example, any food?",
    "answer": "For example, any food has to be already prepared."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Shabbat begins No later than?",
    "answer": "Shabbat begins No later than 18 minutes before sunset, before the family meal begins, the woman of the house lights two Shabbat candles, passes her hands over her eyes and recites a blessing to welcome in Shabbat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The two candles represent sakhor?",
    "answer": "The two candles represent sakhor (to remember Shabbat) and shamor (to observe Shabbat), which come from the two versions of the Ten Commandments in the Torah, which describe Shabbat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Whilst this should happen at?",
    "answer": "Whilst this should happen at a set time, (18 minutes) before Shabbat begins, in those communities living in a country where the starts are only visible very late, it might be done earlier."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It must happen before Shabbat?",
    "answer": "It must happen before Shabbat begins, as it is forbidden to make fire on the Sabbath."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The family attend the synagogue?",
    "answer": "The family attend the synagogue for the day\u2019s evening service."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In many Orthodox and Masorti?",
    "answer": "In many Orthodox and Masorti families, just the men attend."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Shabbat prayers?",
    "answer": "Shabbat prayers are in two parts: Kabbalat Shabbat (six chapters from Psalms) and then Maariv prayers."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of During the second section the?",
    "answer": "During the second section the Amidah is reduced to just seven blessings by omitting the middle twelve (the petitions) to reflect the belief that all is provided on Shabbat."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Instead, new paragraphs?",
    "answer": "Instead, new paragraphs are inserted, reflecting the themes of Shabbat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The family return to?",
    "answer": "The family return to enjoy a leisurely mean."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Before the meal, the man?",
    "answer": "Before the meal, the man of the house blesses the children and then recites the Kiddush (a declaration that the day is holy and a prayer over the wine to sanctify Shabbat)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of During the meal, special songs?",
    "answer": "During the meal, special songs are sung that reflect the themes of Shabbat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of After the meal, another blessing?",
    "answer": "After the meal, another blessing is said, called birkat ha-mazon."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The rest of the evening?",
    "answer": "The rest of the evening is free for family chat, but many choose to talk about their religion and the Torah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is a time when?",
    "answer": "It is a time when families can share their religion."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 42 Tasks: Look at the?",
    "answer": "42 Tasks:  Look at the quotes from Exodus and Deuteronomy."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Why do?",
    "answer": "Why do Jews observe Shabbat?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. What?",
    "answer": "..  What does Shabbat remember?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ..  What sort of \u2018work\u2019?",
    "answer": "..  What sort of \u2018work\u2019 is forbidden on Shabbat?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Explain how Jewish?",
    "answer": "..  Explain how Jewish families prepare for Shabbat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. \u201cAttending the synagogue is?",
    "answer": "..  \u201cAttending the synagogue is an important part of Shabbat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of On Saturday morning, the rituals?",
    "answer": "On Saturday morning, the rituals of Kiddush and the two challah are repeated."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Shabbat services at the synagogue?",
    "answer": "Shabbat services at the synagogue begin early and last for several hours and the whole family will attend."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The reading of the Torah?",
    "answer": "The reading of the Torah is central to the Shabbat service."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Torah scrolls will be?",
    "answer": "The Torah scrolls will be taken from the Aron Hakodesh, processed around the synagogue, before being taken to the bimah to be read."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Torah scrolls are \u2018dressed\u2019?",
    "answer": "The Torah scrolls are \u2018dressed\u2019 whilst not being read, so the coverings are removed before the scrolls are opened and read."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The congregation will all stand?",
    "answer": "The congregation will all stand until the scrolls are on the reading lectern on the bimah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Some will try to touch?",
    "answer": "Some will try to touch their tallit to the casing to show respect."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The same portion of the?",
    "answer": "The same portion of the Torah is read in every synagogue all over the world, and its message will be the focus of a sermon which is delivered by the rabbi."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Siddur (prayer book) is?",
    "answer": "The Siddur (prayer book) is used to structure the service and is ensures that everyone says the right words."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is really important, as?",
    "answer": "It is really important, as the service is long and difficult to follow from memory, especially when in Hebrew."
  },
  {
    "question": "What historical information is provided about is common for?",
    "answer": "It is common for synagogue congregation to share Kiddush after the service; traditionally, wine and cake."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This is, after all, a?",
    "answer": "This is, after all, a time when the community comes together to reinforce their sense of community and friendship."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Whilst many Orthodox Jews spend?",
    "answer": "Whilst many Orthodox Jews spend the afternoon studying the Torah at the synagogue, for many it is really a family time."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is a day of?",
    "answer": "It is a day of rest, so time is given to study of the Torah, Talmud and religion, but also to playing games or just resting/relaxing."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Late afternoon?",
    "answer": "Late afternoon is the time for a light meal \u2013 no one was allowed to work so the meal has to be ready to just put on the table, prepared before Shabbat begins."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Shabbat ends at sundown,?",
    "answer": "Shabbat ends at sundown, when three stars are visible."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The family perform a ritual?",
    "answer": "The family perform a ritual to conclude Shabbat called Havdalah, which means separation, or division."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This recognises the difference between?",
    "answer": "This recognises the difference between the sacred time of Shabbat and the rest of the week."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Blessings?",
    "answer": "Blessings are recited over wine, spices and candles."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The candles are special, having?",
    "answer": "The candles are special, having multiple wicks to represent torchlight."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The spice box is full?",
    "answer": "The spice box is full of aromatic spices and everyone takes a breath of the smell."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Shabbat?",
    "answer": "Shabbat is so special, the knowledge of ending it saddens people, so the scent of the spice is uplifting."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Lighting candles?",
    "answer": "Lighting candles is an act of work and it again indicated the end of Shabbat."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is 42 Tasks:  What?",
    "answer": "42 Tasks:  What is the difference between the Friday and Saturday Shabbat services?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Explain the?",
    "answer": "..  Explain the Saturday Shabbat rituals."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. What will a synagogue?",
    "answer": "..  What will a synagogue congregation do after the Shabbat service?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. What will a family?",
    "answer": "..  What will a family do once home from the Saturday Shabbat service?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Explain how a Jewish?",
    "answer": "..  Explain how a Jewish family separate themselves from Shabbat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Orthodox Jews Walk to the?",
    "answer": "Orthodox Jews Walk to the synagogue as driving is \tconsidered work Whole family goes to the Shabbat \tmorning service Women and men sit separately in the \tsynagogue After synagogue, the family return home for a light meal The males go to \u2018shul\u2019 (the synagogue) Females spend the day studying the \tTorah and Talmud at home Final service at the synagogue is \theld Final meal of Shabbat is shared at \thome The family say \u2018goodbye\u2019 to Shabbat Masorti Jews Tradition in Judaism is very important."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: Jews have always celebrated Shabbat because of the Commandments, therefore they continue the tradition Midrash tells Jews that Shabbat is a sample of the Messianic Age \u2013 how life could be, once the Messiah comes Shabbat is a \u201cqueen\u201d who is with Jews in their home for the whole of Shabbat Reform Jews Light candles before the evening meal, regardless of whether it is sundown or not \t(to not eat too late in Summer or too early in Winter) Kiddush can be recited by any female in the house May drive to the synagogue Families (males and females) sit together to worship During Shabbat, families might help others (tzedakah) or make cards to take to \tolder relatives in care homes?",
    "answer": "Jews have always celebrated Shabbat because of the Commandments, therefore they continue the tradition Midrash tells Jews that Shabbat is a sample of the Messianic Age \u2013 how life could be, once the Messiah comes Shabbat is a \u201cqueen\u201d who is with Jews in their home for the whole of Shabbat Reform Jews Light candles before the evening meal, regardless of whether it is sundown or not \t(to not eat too late in Summer or too early in Winter) Kiddush can be recited by any female in the house May drive to the synagogue Families (males and females) sit together to worship During Shabbat, families might help others (tzedakah) or make cards to take to \tolder relatives in care homes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This could be considered \u2018work\u2019?",
    "answer": "This could be considered \u2018work\u2019 by Orthodox Jews as \tit is an act of creation Shabbat is a time for relaxing, taking time out from the hectic world 42"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 42 Tasks: Explain how different?",
    "answer": "42 Tasks:  Explain how different groups of Jews observe Shabbat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. \u201cThe commandment to observe?",
    "answer": "..  \u201cThe commandment to observe Shabbat is the most important commandment."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In Judaism, the birth ceremony?",
    "answer": "In Judaism, the birth ceremony for boys is called Brit Milah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In Sephardic communities (where Jews?",
    "answer": "In Sephardic communities (where Jews are of Spanish, Middle Eastern or North African heritage) and Italian communities, there is also a tradition of welcoming girls with a celebration called \u2018gift of the daughter\u2019, or \u2018zeved habat\u2019."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The name of the ceremony?",
    "answer": "The name of the ceremony comes from the book of Genesis, in which the matriarch Leah states, following the birth of Zevulun, \u201cG-d grant me a gift."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u201d Brit Milah happens eight?",
    "answer": "\u201d Brit Milah happens eight days after birth, unless there is ill health."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The ceremony happens at home?",
    "answer": "The ceremony happens at home or in shul, as early as possible after Morning Prayer."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of A minyan?",
    "answer": "A minyan should be present."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is A boy?",
    "answer": "A boy is circumcised as a mark of the Covenant between Abraham and the Israelites."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is seen?",
    "answer": "It is seen as a commandment."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is also the rite?",
    "answer": "It is also the rite through which a new-born male becomes part of the Jewish faith."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of If the ceremony takes place?",
    "answer": "If the ceremony takes place in the home, a mohel (man trained to carry out circumcision) goes to the child."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of A kvater (G-dparent) takes the?",
    "answer": "A kvater (G-dparent) takes the child from the mother to give to the father."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of He wears his tallit and?",
    "answer": "He wears his tallit and tefillin, reminding him of the seriousness of this commandment he is following."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of He then gives the boy?",
    "answer": "He then gives the boy to a special, male guest (sandek) who will hold the child whilst the circumcision is carried out."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of From the start of the?",
    "answer": "From the start of the ceremony, candles are lit by those present."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is said that when?",
    "answer": "It is said that when Moses was born, the room was lit up."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of So, lighting candles illuminates the?",
    "answer": "So, lighting candles illuminates the room in the hope that the boy will group up to be a good Jew."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Then the mohel will bless?",
    "answer": "Then the mohel will bless the child as he carries out the circumcision."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The father reads a?",
    "answer": "The father reads a blessing from the Siddur Torah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Finally, after completing the circumcision,?",
    "answer": "Finally, after completing the circumcision, the boy\u2019s name is announced."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The baby is them given?",
    "answer": "The baby is them given to its mother to be fed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is traditional for there?",
    "answer": "It is traditional for there to be a celebratory meal."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of For a girl, it is?",
    "answer": "For a girl, it is customary to name the new-born in the synagogue after the father has been called up to the Torah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This happens on the?",
    "answer": "This happens on the first Shabbat after her birth."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In some communities, this happens?",
    "answer": "In some communities, this happens on the first day after birth at which there is a Torah reading."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In the Sephardi tradition, the?",
    "answer": "In the Sephardi tradition, the congregation will sing songs to welcome her."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It has become tradition for?",
    "answer": "It has become tradition for the parents to treat the congregation to Kiddush in celebration after the service."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is 42 Tasks:  Why?",
    "answer": "42 Tasks:  Why are birth ceremonies important in Judaism?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Describe what happens?",
    "answer": "..  Describe what happens during a Brit Milah ceremony."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Describe the baby?",
    "answer": "..  Describe the baby naming ceremony for girls."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. \u201cNew-born children should always?",
    "answer": "..  \u201cNew-born children should always be welcomes into a religion."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Bar Mitzvah translates as?",
    "answer": "Bar Mitzvah translates as \u2018son of the commandments\u2019."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is a recognition of?",
    "answer": "It is a recognition of the fact that a young man has reached the age by which he is personally responsible for his religious acts, and is marked by his first reading in the synagogue of the Torah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of From this point on, he?",
    "answer": "From this point on, he is regarded as an adult in all religious aspects, for example, he should use tefillin in prayers and can count as one of the ten needed for a minyan."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In fact, he remains Bar?",
    "answer": "In fact, he remains Bar Mitzvah all of his life, it is not just for one day, as it refers to the duty of keeping the mitzvot, which is incumbent on all Jews."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Males lead the service in?",
    "answer": "Males lead the service in an Orthodox shul and so reading from the Torah is a way of showing the change in status from a child to an adult."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the role of girls have different?",
    "answer": "Girls have different roles within Jewish life and so they have different ceremonies."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Girls reach the age of?",
    "answer": "Girls reach the age of maturity at 12, so it is common to recognise that through the Bat Mitzvah ceremony."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of There is no special ceremony,?",
    "answer": "There is no special ceremony, and it is common, especially in the Orthodox community, to celebrate this at home, with the girl reciting a blessing and talking about the importance of the day."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In the Reform and Liberal,?",
    "answer": "In the Reform and Liberal, and many of the conservative traditions, in recognition of changing societal norms and a sense of equality, there are special events in the synagogue."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In the Reform and Liberal?",
    "answer": "In the Reform and Liberal traditions, a girl may read the Torah at the synagogue, so the ceremony will be the same regardless of gender."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is the day when,?",
    "answer": "It is the day when, religiously, the child becomes an adult The child consciously steps into the responsibility of being one of G-d\u2019s chosen people The child confirms their wish \tto keep the religion going It is a central rite of passage \tto Judaism Bar/Bat Mitzvah reinforces a \tperson\u2019s faith and enables \tthem to understand it more It promotes togetherness \twithin the community It binds the person to their \tcommunity 42"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Celebrating the occasion Although the?",
    "answer": "Celebrating the occasion Although the idea of Bar Mitzvah is in the Talmud, the custom of celebrating only began about six hundred years ago."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is common to give?",
    "answer": "It is common to give gifts to the young person and to have a family meal."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Some families will pay for?",
    "answer": "Some families will pay for Kiddush at the synagogue for the congregation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Some Jews believe that celebrations?",
    "answer": "Some Jews believe that celebrations should be low-key, as there is no scriptural basis for over the top celebrations, like lavish parties."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Certainly, a Bat Mitzvah celebration?",
    "answer": "Certainly, a Bat Mitzvah celebration in the Orthodox community will be low-key."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of However it is becoming more?",
    "answer": "However it is becoming more and more common for Jews to go abroad to celebrate, wither to the Western Wall in Jerusalem, or to a place which is important in their family history."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The ceremony Anyone undergoing the?",
    "answer": "The ceremony Anyone undergoing the ceremony has to be prepares and be able to do well in the ceremony, so there is a period of preparation during which a religious person will instruct the young person in how to read and handle the Torah, as well as how to perform other religious obligations such as how to wear tefillin."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is quite common for?",
    "answer": "It is quite common for young people to spend months studying the portion of the Torah they will read, and learning to wear the tefillin correctly."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of For a boy, the ceremony?",
    "answer": "For a boy, the ceremony takes place on the Shabbat after his 13th birthday as part of the usual service at the synagogue."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of On the day of the?",
    "answer": "On the day of the Bar Mitzvah the Torah scroll is prepared on the bimah and then the rabbi calls the boy to read to the rest of the congregation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of He goes up to the?",
    "answer": "He goes up to the bimah and reads the passages in Hebrew for the Sabbath service."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of His father will then make?",
    "answer": "His father will then make a particular blessing: \u2018Blessed is he who has freed me from the liability of this one."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u201d The Midrash states that?",
    "answer": "\u201d The Midrash states that a father is obligated to concern himself with the upbringing of his son until the age of thirteen, so when he becomes Bar Mitzvah, he is released from that duty."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is his natural father?",
    "answer": "It is his natural father who must make the blessings, according to Jewish law."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In some communities, the boy?",
    "answer": "In some communities, the boy will read all of the Torah portions and will also lead the congregation in their prayers, which is a demonstration of them accepting him as an adult."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The rabbi then gives his?",
    "answer": "The rabbi then gives his sermon, part of this is for the boy to remind him of his duty to keep the commandments throughout his life."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Finally, he is blessed by?",
    "answer": "Finally, he is blessed by the rabbi with the words, \u2018The Lord bless thee and keep thee."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u2019 Kiddush after the service?",
    "answer": "\u2019 Kiddush after the service allow s the congregation to celebrate this event, and there is often a big family celebration."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of For Reform, Liberal and many?",
    "answer": "For Reform, Liberal and many Masorti Jews, the girl\u2019s Bat Mitzvah would follow the same process in the synagogue, Some Masorti congregations do not allow girls to read the Torah and so will do the ceremony on the Friday evening, when the girl will recite the Prophetic reading which is to be read on the Saturday."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Friday would not?",
    "answer": "Friday would not normally have readings."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of For Orthodox Jews, the occasion?",
    "answer": "For Orthodox Jews, the occasion is usually low-key, more of a private family affair, celebrated by a modest meal, blessings and new clothes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of However in some Orthodox communities,?",
    "answer": "However in some Orthodox communities, girls are now being allowed synagogue Bat Mitzvah, or allowed to address the congregation with a reading about their new religious status, which they would have written after doing their own research."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In the Reform tradition, it?",
    "answer": "In the Reform tradition, it is not unusual to see a young person design part of their own Bar/Bat Mitzvah ceremony, including giving them sermons after research and study."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Describe the ceremony?",
    "answer": "..  Describe the ceremony for a Bar Mitzvah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Describe the celebrations?",
    "answer": "..  Describe the celebrations for a Bat Mitzvah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. \u201cBar Mitzvah is more?",
    "answer": "..  \u201cBar Mitzvah is more of a celebration than a serious religious event."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is This ceremony?",
    "answer": "This ceremony is full of custom and tradition."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Marriage?",
    "answer": "Marriage is a fulfilment of the commandment in Genesis 1:28: \u201cBe fruitful and multiply."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u201d In Judaism, having children?",
    "answer": "\u201d In Judaism, having children was only rightly done within marriage; hence marriage being necessary to fulfil one of the earliest commands given to humans."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of However, it is not?",
    "answer": "However, it is not just about having children."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is seen as the?",
    "answer": "It is seen as the natural state of things to be married."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of From the time of Adam,?",
    "answer": "From the time of Adam, Eve was created as a helper and a companion for him, and so giving a template for living."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is seen as a?",
    "answer": "It is seen as a blessing as it helps to overcome loneliness; both actual and spiritual loneliness."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The idea is that the?",
    "answer": "The idea is that the two partners complete each other; that marriage is a natural state and a blessing from G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Ceremony In Talmudic times?",
    "answer": "The Ceremony In Talmudic times (70BCE to 500CE), there was a betrothal ceremony called a kiddushin and a separate marriage ceremony."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of These are now done either?",
    "answer": "These are now done either side of the reading of the ketubah (marriage contract)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The betrothal ceremony begins with?",
    "answer": "The betrothal ceremony begins with the veiled bride approaching and circling her husband to be."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Two blessings?",
    "answer": "Two blessings are recited over wine; a blessing over wine, and one about the commandments of marriage."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The man will then place?",
    "answer": "The man will then place the ring on his bride-to-be\u2019s finger."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The ring (or rings in?",
    "answer": "The ring (or rings in Reform Judaism) must be an undecorated, unbroken circle, showing the hope for a harmonious marriage."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The husband will recite from?",
    "answer": "The husband will recite from the Talmud: \u2018With this ring, you are wedded to me in accordance with the laws of Moses and Israel."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u2019 It is put on?",
    "answer": "\u2019 It is put on the forefinger of her right hand, and she then puts it on the ring finger on her left."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This usually happens under?",
    "answer": "This usually happens under the huppah (wedding canopy)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Next, the ketubah is?",
    "answer": "Next, the ketubah is signed in front of witnesses."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It details the legal terms?",
    "answer": "It details the legal terms of the marriage; what is payable to her if the husband dies, or they divorce."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It can be read aloud?",
    "answer": "It can be read aloud so that it is witnessed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The bride walks around the?",
    "answer": "The bride walks around the groom (three times in some traditions, seven in others)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u2018I betroth?",
    "answer": "\u2018I betroth you\u2019 three times."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The huppah represents?",
    "answer": "The huppah represents the marriage bedroom."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: Traditionally, weddings happen in the open air because of the blessing to Abraham that his children would be as numerous as the stars?",
    "answer": "Traditionally, weddings happen in the open air because of the blessing to Abraham that his children would be as numerous as the stars."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The rabbi might make a?",
    "answer": "The rabbi might make a speech about the responsibilities of the marriage and about the couple."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Seven blessings?",
    "answer": "Seven blessings are said for the couple in the presence of the minyan, the fifth and sixth of which are specifically about marriage."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The bride and groom share?",
    "answer": "The bride and groom share a glass of wine and more blessings may be bestowed by the rabbi."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Finally the groom crushes a?",
    "answer": "Finally the groom crushes a glass under his foot to remember the destruction of the Temple in Jerusalem."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The act of breaking the?",
    "answer": "The act of breaking the glass also remind the couple that in times of joy, they must remain aware that there can be sadness and trouble, and to remain mindful helps them to manage those difficult times."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In most traditions, they go?",
    "answer": "In most traditions, they go to a private room for about five minutes, this is called \u2018Yichud\u2019 (privacy)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Today, it also gives them?",
    "answer": "Today, it also gives them a moment\u2019s peace in an otherwise hectic day."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of With this act,?",
    "answer": "With this act, the marriage is complete."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Some different traditions Before the?",
    "answer": "Some different traditions Before the ceremony: most Jews fast before the \tceremony, and most do not allow the couple to see \teach other on the day of the ceremony."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In the Orthodox tradition it?",
    "answer": "In the \tOrthodox tradition it is common for the couple to not \tsee each other the whole week before."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Aufruf: on Shabbat morning before?",
    "answer": "Aufruf: on Shabbat morning before the wedding, it is \ttraditional in Orthodox Judaism for the groom to attend \tsynagogue, be called up to read the Torah and receive \tthe congratulations of the congregation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In many communities, he will?",
    "answer": "In many \tcommunities, he will be showered with nuts, almonds and \traisins, or more commonly today, sweets."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of These symbolise that the bridegroom\u2019s?",
    "answer": "These symbolise \tthat the bridegroom\u2019s sins are forgiven and all will be \t\u2018sweet\u2019 or good."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Kabbalat Panim: Jewish Orthodox weddings?",
    "answer": "Kabbalat Panim: Jewish Orthodox weddings start with a reception \u2013 separate for men and women."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The groom greets his guests,?",
    "answer": "The groom greets his guests, who sing for him and toast his happiness and health."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The bride sits on a?",
    "answer": "The bride sits on a throne to greet her guests."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The mothers-in-law will break some?",
    "answer": "The mothers-in-law will break some pottery to show that marriage is a serious undertaking, and just as a broken plate cannot be properly repaired, neither can a broken marriage \u2013 so they must work at it."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Veiling the bride: in the?",
    "answer": "Veiling the bride: in the \tAskhenazi tradition, the groom \twill go to the bride and put a \tveil over her face, which she \twears until they leave the \thuppah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This has Biblical origins as?",
    "answer": "This has \tBiblical origins as Rebecca \tcovered her face before \tmarrying Isaac."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Or alternatively, recalls that Jacob?",
    "answer": "Or alternatively, \trecalls that Jacob was tricked \tinto marrying Leah when he should have been marrying Rachel, but her father had veiled her for the wedding and Jacob only saw her face once married."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In some Masorti and Reform?",
    "answer": "In some Masorti and Reform synagogues now, the bride reciprocates by putting a kippah on the groom\u2019s head, or cloaking hi m in a tallit."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Circling the huppah: in Orthodox?",
    "answer": "Circling the huppah: in Orthodox traditions, it is done seven times to represent the seven days of creation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In some?",
    "answer": "In some traditions, just three."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is 53 Tasks:  Why?",
    "answer": "53 Tasks:  Why is marriage important in Judaism?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Using the following words,?",
    "answer": ".. Using the following words, describe the marriage ceremony: kiddushin; ketubah; rings; huppah; wine  \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Describe the wedding customs?",
    "answer": "..  Describe the wedding customs associated with different Jewish traditions."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Describe the symbolism?",
    "answer": "..  Describe the symbolism in a Jewish wedding ceremony."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. \u201cMarriage ceremonies should?",
    "answer": "..  \u201cMarriage ceremonies should not be dictated by tradition."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of When a person dies: The?",
    "answer": "When a person dies: The deceased is entitled to almost the same level of respect and dignity as a living person."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of At death, the eyes of?",
    "answer": "At death, the eyes of the deceased must be closed, if not already."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Some believe that a person?",
    "answer": "Some believe that a person cannot look on to this life and the life to come at the same time, so by closing the eyes, we close off this life and allow them to see the next."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of There is also scriptural?",
    "answer": "There is also scriptural authority to do this."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: The body will be covered, because a dead body is unbecoming, and people should remember the deceased as when they were alive rather than dead?",
    "answer": "The body will be covered, because a dead body is unbecoming, and people should remember the deceased as when they were alive rather than dead."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: The body is put on the ground because it is a source of defilement, and anything it touches (or that touches it) becomes impure \u2013 except the ground?",
    "answer": "The body is put on the ground because it is a source of defilement, and anything it touches (or that touches it) becomes impure \u2013 except the ground."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Candles?",
    "answer": "Candles are lit and places at the head, recognising Proverbs 6:23: \u201cFor the commandment is a lamp and the law a light."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: \u201d The corpse will be continually watched until burial to ensure the proper treatment, and because it is believed that the soul will only leave at this point?",
    "answer": "\u201d The corpse will be continually watched until burial to ensure the proper treatment, and because it is believed that the soul will only leave at this point."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of So it is reasonable to?",
    "answer": "So it is reasonable to think that the soul would be in distress at the death, and someone witting with it is a comfort."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They will?",
    "answer": "They will recite Psalms constantly."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Each community has a Hevrah?",
    "answer": "Each community has a Hevrah Kadishah (Holy Society) whose members are dedicated to preparing the body for and burying the dead."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They will work with the?",
    "answer": "They will work with the funeral parlour to wash the body, dress it in white linen shrouds (showing all are equal in death)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of For male deceased, they are?",
    "answer": "For male deceased, they are wrapped in their tallit, less one of its tzitzit, so that it is not a holy article, and that they no longer have to fulfil the commandments."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The act of washing is?",
    "answer": "The act of washing is done according to Jewish law and has both physical and spiritual elements."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The work of Hevrah Kadishah?",
    "answer": "The work of Hevrah Kadishah can be said to represent the last link in a chain of care and concern for the dead."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Hevrah Kadishah keep?",
    "answer": "The Hevrah Kadishah keep the mitzvot of tahara."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Tahara?",
    "answer": "Tahara is \u2018purification\u2019 and is the term used to prepare the deceased for their final resting place 53"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Being part of the Hevrah?",
    "answer": "Being part of the Hevrah Kadishah is all about teamwork."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They are carrying?",
    "answer": "They are carrying out a \tsacred task."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of We act in the?",
    "answer": "We act in the spirit of chesed (kindness)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The work of the?",
    "answer": "The work of the Hevrah Kadhishah is so important."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is such a kindness?",
    "answer": "It is such a kindness \u2013 and the \tdead cannot reward this kindness."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The burial Jews are?",
    "answer": "The burial Jews are always buried (not cremated)."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Genesis 3:19 says, \u201cman?",
    "answer": "Genesis 3:19 says, \u201cman is formed from dust, and returns to it."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u201d The burial happens as?",
    "answer": "\u201d The burial happens as soon after the death as possible, preferably on the same day."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of However, burials may not happen?",
    "answer": "However, burials may not happen on Shabbat or on festival days."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The casket must?",
    "answer": "The casket must be made of wood."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of A service may be held?",
    "answer": "A service may be held in the chapel of rest or at the graveside, following a similar process for either."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Kari\u2019ah: the ritual of?",
    "answer": "Kari\u2019ah: the ritual of rending garments is observed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Different communities do?",
    "answer": "Different communities do this at different stages."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Orthodox do it straight?",
    "answer": "The Orthodox do it straight after death, others before the funeral procession or at the burial."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Mourners\u2019 clothes are torn deliberately?",
    "answer": "Mourners\u2019 clothes are torn deliberately through the material (not along a seam) to represent emotional need and sadness."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Many non-Orthodox Jews no longer?",
    "answer": "Many non-Orthodox Jews no longer tear clothes, but rather wear a strip of black ribbon on their outer garment."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In the Reform tradition, this?",
    "answer": "In the Reform tradition, this is given to them at the funeral."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The casket is carried to?",
    "answer": "The casket is carried to the grave, with seven stops made along the way."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This shows how difficult the?",
    "answer": "This shows how difficult the task is and also that there is no desire to hurriedly complete it."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The casket is lowered into?",
    "answer": "The casket is lowered into the grave, with the head facing east, as it is believed that the dead will resurrect to rise facing east (to Jerusalem)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Either during or just after?",
    "answer": "Either during or just after this, prayers will be recited."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is El Malei Rachamim (prayer of mercy)?",
    "answer": "El Malei Rachamim (prayer of mercy) is recited at the graveside, or sung by the cantor, followed by the mourner\u2019s Kaddish, by the family."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is customary for those?",
    "answer": "It is customary for those attending to help fill the grave."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is A shovel?",
    "answer": "A shovel is used, which each person puts down on the ground when they have used it, symbolising that they do not want to pass sorrow to the next person."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Others throw soil?",
    "answer": "Others throw soil onto the casket."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This ritual shows?",
    "answer": "This ritual shows service and love."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The men in attendance make?",
    "answer": "The men in attendance make two lines between which the bereaved pass."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The lines will murmur blessings?",
    "answer": "The lines will murmur blessings on the bereaved: \u201cMay G-d console you among the other mourners of Zion and Jerusalem."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u201d On returning from the?",
    "answer": "\u201d On returning from the funeral, the first meal must be brought by neighbours and friends."
  },
  {
    "question": "What historical information is provided about traditionally is a?",
    "answer": "It traditionally is a dairy-based meal (no meat) and it is customary for it to include egg (new life) and bread (staff of life)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Many of the meals consumed?",
    "answer": "Many of the meals consumed by the bereaved during the next seven days will be brought to them as gifts of comfort by members of the community, which is part of the love and care given to mourners."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 53 Tasks: Explain the?",
    "answer": "53 Tasks:  Explain the work of the Hevrah Kadishah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Describe in detail the?",
    "answer": "..  Describe in detail the funeral service, explaining the symbolism within it."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. \u201cFuneral ceremonies benefit?",
    "answer": "..  \u201cFuneral ceremonies benefit the living, not the dead."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Judaism tried to control the?",
    "answer": "Judaism tried to control the mourning period and shape it so as to help the bereaved face reality of having to move on."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of There are four parts?",
    "answer": "There are four parts to the period of mourning."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Aninut: the period between?",
    "answer": "Aninut: the period between death and the burial."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of During this period, the bereaved?",
    "answer": "During this period, the bereaved is excused from any and all commandments, even reciting Shema."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They may not wear tefillin,?",
    "answer": "They may not wear tefillin, cannot eat/drink at a festive table, cut their hair, wash their clothes, bathe themselves or have sexual relations."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Shiv\u2019ah: meaning \u2018seven\u2019?",
    "answer": "Shiv\u2019ah: meaning \u2018seven\u2019 is the seven days from closing the grave."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Only bereaved parents, siblings, children?",
    "answer": "Only bereaved parents, siblings, children or spouses observe this period and the remaining two."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: It is often known as \u2018sitting Shiv\u2019ah\u2019 because of the practice of sitting on a low stool and not working?",
    "answer": "It is often known as \u2018sitting Shiv\u2019ah\u2019 because of the practice of sitting on a low stool and not working."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The prohibitions of Aninut remain?",
    "answer": "The prohibitions of Aninut remain in place, plus they may not greet people, study the Torah (other than laws of mourning, or tracts about suffering, for example, the book of Job), or sit in chairs."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of All the mirrors in the?",
    "answer": "All the mirrors in the house are covered and a candle is lit which will last for seven days."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Some rabbis suggested that people?",
    "answer": "Some rabbis suggested that people should not attend the home to pay their condolences on the first three days, as the sadness is too raw."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of People can go to?",
    "answer": "People can go to help comfort the bereaved."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They might take?",
    "answer": "They might take food as a gift."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Daily prayers will be held?",
    "answer": "Daily prayers will be held in the house of the deceased in many communities, which a minyan in attendance."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The bereaved will go to?",
    "answer": "The bereaved will go to Shabbat prayer, being greeted at the door by members of the congregation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is customary for them?",
    "answer": "It is customary for them to sit in a different place to their normal spot, which heightens their sense of loss and grief, as it is unfamiliar."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Sheloshim: meaning \u201930 days\u2019, which?",
    "answer": "Sheloshim: meaning \u201930 days\u2019, which includes the 7 of Shiv\u2019ah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Some of the restrictions are?",
    "answer": "Some of the restrictions are now lifted \u2013 they bathe (for cleanliness not pleasure) and go to work; all others are kept."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Avelut: the?",
    "answer": "Avelut: the next 11 months."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of For those who have lost?",
    "answer": "For those who have lost a parent, mourning will continue for a full eleven months."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of All the Sheloshim prohibitions are?",
    "answer": "All the Sheloshim prohibitions are not lifted, though happy events, for example, weddings, should be avoided."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of From the burial for eleven?",
    "answer": "From the burial for eleven months, the bereaved son will recite the mourners\u2019 Kaddish at synagogue."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the helps of the belief is that this?",
    "answer": "The belief is that this helps release the dead person from any sins 60"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of they have committed, showing they?",
    "answer": "they have committed, showing they were not a complete sinner."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of That the Kaddish is recited?",
    "answer": "That the Kaddish is recited for eleven not twelve months, indicates that there was at least some good in the person, according to some scholars."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Remembering the dead The law?",
    "answer": "Remembering the dead The law requires these to ensure the dead are not forgotten and also that the burial place is not desecrated."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of A gravestone makes it certain?",
    "answer": "A gravestone makes it certain they cannot be forgotten, and that the grave is clear for all to see."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In Israel, the erection of?",
    "answer": "In Israel, the erection of the gravestone happens at the end of Shiv\u2019ah or shlosim."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is customary to have?",
    "answer": "It is customary to have an unveiling ceremony for the stone after the first year after the death."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In some communities, this is?",
    "answer": "In some communities, this is when the gravestone is actually placed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Yahrzeit and Yizkor Each anniversary?",
    "answer": "Yahrzeit and Yizkor Each anniversary of the death of a parent is recalled by Yahrzeit."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Most Jews who have lost?",
    "answer": "Most Jews who have lost their parents will fast on this day, though Hasidic Jews have a celebration to recognise that their loved one is in the next life."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of A candle will be?",
    "answer": "A candle will be lit which lasts 24 hours."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Many Jews take time in?",
    "answer": "Many Jews take time in the day to study Torah and it is customary for them to donate tzedakah (charity) on this day."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Yizkor is a memorial?",
    "answer": "The Yizkor is a memorial prayer that is recited by mourners in the synagogue on specific festival days: Yom Kippur, Sh\u2019mini Atzeret, the eighth day of Pesach and the second day of Shavuout."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 60 Tasks: How do practices?",
    "answer": "60 Tasks:  How do practices in Judaism help and comfort mourners?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. How does bereavement?",
    "answer": "..  How does bereavement impact on a person\u2019s life?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Describe the four stages?",
    "answer": "..  Describe the four stages of mourning and explain the symbolism involved."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. \u201cIt is too difficult?",
    "answer": ".. \t\u201cIt is too difficult to complete Jewish mourning rituals in today\u2019s world."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Jewish New Year (High Holy?",
    "answer": "Jewish New Year (High Holy Day) Happens on the first day of the months of Tishri (in September/October) Rosh Hashanah begins a 10-day period of reflection and repentance which ends \ton Yom Kippur Focuses on the individual and their way of living on earth All Jews observe the festival for two days, other than Reform, who give one day Rosh Hashanah represents the day G-d created the world, so you could see it as the world\u2019s birthday, which is actually emphasised in the Talmud."
  },
  {
    "question": "What historical information is provided about its focus around?",
    "answer": "Given its focus around repentance, or being truly sorry for wrongs/sins done, it is referred to as the Day of Awe, as Jews believe that on this day all humankind stands before the throne of G-d to give a full account of all they have done in the past year, so that they can be judged."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Jews hope to receive a?",
    "answer": "Jews hope to receive a promise of mercy from G-d and the ten days are their chance to make sure of that."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Talmud says that there?",
    "answer": "The Talmud says that there are three books of: the Wicked, the Righteous and the in-between."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The idea of the books?",
    "answer": "The idea of the books is figurative, as G-d does not actually need to write down this information."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of In these books are recorded?",
    "answer": "In these books are recorded the deeds of every person and thus their destiny for the next year is fixed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The righteous gain another year?",
    "answer": "The righteous gain another year of life, the wicked do not, but those in-between have the chance over Rosh Hashanah to make repentance for anything, so secure another year."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The greeting, \u201cMay you be?",
    "answer": "The greeting, \u201cMay you be inscribed with a good year,\u201d is said often at this time and refers to these books."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Even though there is a?",
    "answer": "Even though there is a hugely solemn side to the festival, it is joyous and festive."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The associated colour is white,?",
    "answer": "The associated colour is white, so white clothes are worn."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Customs of Rosh Hashanah Sounding?",
    "answer": "Customs of Rosh Hashanah Sounding of the shofar (horn) to make three notes as \ta call to repentance."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This ritual starts a month?",
    "answer": "This ritual starts a month before \tRosh Hashanah, giving advanced warning so that \tJews can prepare  Reciting Tashlich \u2013 Jews go to the riverbank, recite \tMicah 7:18-20 and Psalms 33 and 130, the shake out \ttheir pockets to symbolically cast their sins into the \twater  Many Jews do not sleep during the first night of Rosh \tHashanah, dedicating the day and night to prayer, \tmeditation and soul-searching."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Staying awake?",
    "answer": "Staying awake is a custom now to maximise the \tpersonal, spiritual focus  Attending the synagogue for the special midnight \tservice."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Prayers about saying sorry and seeking \tforgiveness?",
    "answer": "Prayers about saying sorry and seeking \tforgiveness are said  Sweet food is favoured for Rosh \tHashanah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Their seeds represent the hope?",
    "answer": "Their \tseeds represent the hope that a \tperson will perform many good \tdeeds in the year to come  Traditional family meal at home \twith round challah bread, to \tsymbolise eternal life or the \tjourney upwards."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Fish?",
    "answer": "Fish is \tcommonly served to reflect that \tfish multiply quickly, and so the \thope to fulfil the commandment \tto multiply from G-d for all Jews 60"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is 60 Tasks:  What?",
    "answer": "60 Tasks:  What is Rosh Hashanah?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Which other festival?",
    "answer": "..  Which other festival is linked with Rosh Hashanah?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Explain how observing Rosh?",
    "answer": "..  Explain how observing Rosh Hashanah can influence a Jewish person\u2019s life."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Yom Kippur?",
    "answer": "Yom Kippur is a Day of Atonement."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Over the period of Rosh?",
    "answer": "Over the period of Rosh Hashanah, people think about what they have done and try to redeem themselves."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Everyone can find their way?",
    "answer": "Everyone can find their way back to G-d, so no one should lose faith if they show self-discipline."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The aims of Yom Kippur?",
    "answer": "The aims of Yom Kippur are summed up by Maimonides who said that repentance is when a sinner casts sins from his mind and resolves in his heart to sin no more."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is believed that the?",
    "answer": "It is believed that the say brings pardon for sin between humans and G-d; forgiveness only comes if an attempt is made to repair any damage done."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Reparation (making up)?",
    "answer": "Reparation (making up) comes before everything else."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Before Yom Kippur begins: A lavish meal?",
    "answer": "Before Yom Kippur begins: A lavish meal is shared to strengthen people ahead of the fast."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Some believe it is to?",
    "answer": "Some believe it is to \tmake the fast more difficult The Kol Nidre service and prayer is chanted, asking for release from rash promises \tmade to G-d Yom Kippur is a day of fasting."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Only children, the ill, pregnant?",
    "answer": "Only children, the ill, pregnant women and those who have recently given birth are excluded from fasting."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Taking prescribed medication?",
    "answer": "Taking prescribed medication is allowed Jews wear white and cheerfulness should be a characteristic of the day This is the day that the book of life closes, so it is a realisation that all sins can be \treleased and being thankful that G-d is loving and merciful Services at the synagogue all have the theme of confession and repentance Readings reflect the theme, e."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of g. Jonah, who abandons his?",
    "answer": "g. Jonah, who abandons his evil ways and accepts \tresponsibility for his actions and returns to G-d The service also includes memorial prayers (Yizkor) A shofar blast sounds the end of Yom Kippur and fasting 60"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 60 Tasks: What does?",
    "answer": "60 Tasks:  What does Yom Kippur mean for Jews?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. What happens?",
    "answer": "..  What happens before Yom Kippur begins?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. How does the festival?",
    "answer": "..  How does the festival of Yom Kippur influence the life of a Jew?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Pesach begins on the first?",
    "answer": "Pesach begins on the first day of the Jewish calendar called the \u2018chief of months\u2019."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is a festival of?",
    "answer": "It is a festival of joy, even though it recalls events of great sadness."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Many Jews would say this?",
    "answer": "Many Jews would say this is the most anticipated and most celebrated of all Jewish festivals and rituals."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is one of the?",
    "answer": "It is one of the three pilgrim festivals, where Jews had to attend the Temple to make a sacrifice."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It is celebrated for seven?",
    "answer": "It is celebrated for seven days in Israel, with the first and last days being key, and outside Israel it is an 8-day festival, with Seder meals on the first two days."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is A Seder meal?",
    "answer": "A Seder meal is one attended by the extended family to retell the story of the Exodus."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Reform and Conservative Jews across?",
    "answer": "Reform and Conservative Jews across the world celebrate for seven days."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The celebration is very uniform,?",
    "answer": "The celebration is very uniform, whichever type of Jew is celebrating it \u2013 it is important that all Jews celebrate Pesach the same."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Much of the festival is?",
    "answer": "Much of the festival is based around the home; certainly the key customs are, which many believe has enriched home-life, as well as reinforcing the religion and understanding of the history."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The origins of Pesach Pesach?",
    "answer": "The origins of Pesach Pesach remember the liberation of the Israelites from slavery in Egypt over 3000 years ago."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It brings Jews into close?",
    "answer": "It brings Jews into close contact with their history and the liberation, allowing them to celebrate their freedom and reminding them to continue to fight for freedom in every generation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of It also emphasises that G-d?",
    "answer": "It also emphasises that G-d will ultimately come to the aid of his people."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The impact of Pesach?",
    "answer": "The impact of Pesach last all year, e."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of g. when a person thinks?",
    "answer": "g. when a person thinks back and relishes their freedom, as granted by G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of As well as this, there?",
    "answer": "As well as this, there is the blessing \u201cnext year in Jerusalem,\u201d which shows the hope that Jerusalem can be rebuilt as the spiritual centre of the world, not just that they might enjoy the festival there one day."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Five key concepts of Pesach?",
    "answer": "Five key concepts of Pesach Memory: only by becoming aware of the past can our lives become fulfilled with meaning and purpose."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The past gives clued to?",
    "answer": "The past gives clued to the now and the future Optimism/hope: without hope, the Israelites would not have survived."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Jews?",
    "answer": "Jews are reminded to retain hope Faith (belief): Jewish optimism comes from the firmly held belief that they are blessed with support from above by a caring G-d."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the effects described in this statement: This faith leads to faith in self, the future and an ability to help change the world Family (belongings): In the home is sown the seeds of the future because the children are the future?",
    "answer": "This faith leads to faith in self, the future and an ability to help change the world Family (belongings): In the home is sown the seeds of the future because the children are the future."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of They need to be educated?",
    "answer": "They need to be educated and reminded about this festival Responsibility to others: The experience of the Israelites shines a light on the need for people to care for others."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of This includes feeding the poor,?",
    "answer": "This includes feeding the poor, fighting injustice, supporting the oppressed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Chased and tzedakah?",
    "answer": "Chased and tzedakah are crucial principles Getting ready for Pesach Prayers on the morning before Pesach begins First-born sons attend the synagogue for a study \tsession, led by the rabbi Most Jews give to charity directly before Pesach Leavened food (chametz) must be cleared from \tthe house by 10am on the morning as Pesach \tbegins."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of When they have collected ten?",
    "answer": "When \tthey have collected ten \u2018planted\u2019 pieces of bread, all is wrapped up and left for the morning, when it is burned Some Jewish families have a special set of kitchenware for Pesach, so as to avoid \tany leavened goods Pesach is linked to spring, so it is traditional that families have a spring-clean of their \thouse New clothes may be bought Special food is prepared and eaten, reinforcing that it is a joyful festival 60"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Wine?",
    "answer": "Wine is drunk and it is traditional to spill 10 drops, to represent each of the 10 plagues."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Elijah\u2019s cup (of wine) remains?",
    "answer": "Elijah\u2019s cup (of wine) remains untouched and is there for any stranger who turned up."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of However, Elijah was a prophet?",
    "answer": "However, Elijah was a prophet and is a reminder of the Messianic Age, as he will reappear to herald it in."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The door to the house?",
    "answer": "The door to the house will be opened twice near the end of the service."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of The Orthodox believe the Messianic?",
    "answer": "The Orthodox believe the Messianic Age could come at any time, so this is an even more important ritual."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 60 What does?",
    "answer": "60 What does Pesach mean for Jews?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of .. Explain the symbolism?",
    "answer": "..  Explain the symbolism of the Seder meal."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Exam-style questions What?",
    "answer": "Exam-style questions What is the Talmud?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is (1 mark) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 What?",
    "answer": "(1 mark) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 What is the Halakah?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of (1 mark) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 What?",
    "answer": "(1 mark) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 What two foods can Jews not eat together?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of (1 mark) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 Where?",
    "answer": "(1 mark) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 Where is the Torah kept in the synagogue?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of (1 mark) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 Name?",
    "answer": "(1 mark) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 Name one item found on the Seder plate."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is (1 mark) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 Name a place of pilgrimage for Jews (1 mark) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 What?",
    "answer": "(1 mark) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 Name a place of pilgrimage for Jews (1 mark) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 What is meant by \u2018treyfah\u2019?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of (1 mark)?",
    "answer": "(1 mark) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 60"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Give two religious reasons?",
    "answer": "Give two religious reasons why Jews must marry."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of (2 marks) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 Name?",
    "answer": "(2 marks) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 Name two key features of a synagogue."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of (2 marks) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 Give?",
    "answer": "(2 marks) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 Give two religious reasons why Jews celebrate Pesach."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of (2 marks)?",
    "answer": "(2 marks) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 60"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Explain two contrasting Jewish views?",
    "answer": "Explain two contrasting Jewish views about the importance of the synagogue."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of (4 marks) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026?",
    "answer": "(4 marks) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 Explain two contrasting Jewish rituals which are carried out during Pesach."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is (4 marks) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 Explain two contrasting ways in which worship?",
    "answer": "(4 marks) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 Explain two contrasting ways in which worship is carried out in the synagogue by reform and orthodox Jews."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of (4 marks) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026?",
    "answer": "(4 marks) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 60"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 60 Explain two ways?",
    "answer": "60 Explain two ways in which Jews celebrate Pesach."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of Refer to Jewish?",
    "answer": "Refer to Jewish teachings in your answer."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of (5 marks) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026?",
    "answer": "(5 marks) \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 Explain two ways in which Jews celebrate Shabbat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026?",
    "answer": "\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 Explain two ways in which Jews keep the mitzvot."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 60 \u201cThe home is more?",
    "answer": "60 \u201cThe home is more important than the synagogue for the learning of religion ."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of You should: Refer to Jewish?",
    "answer": "You should:  Refer to Jewish teaching Give developed arguments to support this statement Give developed arguments to support a different point of view Reach a justified conclusion \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 60 \u201cFestivals just remember the?",
    "answer": "60 \u201cFestivals just remember the past and are pointless in modern life."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is 60 \u201cPrayer?",
    "answer": "60 \u201cPrayer is more important than action in the world today."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 60 \u201cJews should be able?",
    "answer": "60 \u201cJews should be able to live as they want."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 60 \u201cThe Torah is the?",
    "answer": "60 \u201cThe Torah is the most important sacred text in Judaism."
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the significance of 60 \u201cKeeping kosher is?",
    "answer": "60 \u201cKeeping kosher is too hard in modern times."
  }
]